[instrumental music playing]
[car alarm beeping]
[dogs barking, siren wailing]
[helicopter hovering]
They're all here?
Of course, they're all here.
I told Naja Naja
I'd get 'em, didn't I?
[prisoners crying]
Do they have
enough air in there, brother?
Last time,
there wasn't enough air.
Yeah, yeah.
You make one mistake...
Don't worry.
They've got air, food, water.
It's like a cruise ship.
Hmm, good.
[door slams]
We get this shipment
to the ceremony,
our Lord might give you
another chance.
Maybe you'll survive
in Kali Yuga's new world.
You think so?
Oh, man...
We'll get them there on time.
I promise, Chen.
Kobra can count on me.
- [glass breaks]
- [all gasp]
Don't lose your head.
Back to back.
Shoot at anything that moves.
It's the bat.
It's gotta be the bat!
[suspenseful music playing]
There! [gun firing]
Did we get him?
[Azrael] You cavort with demons
and call them gods!
[gun cocking]
You embrace the darkness
and treat it as if it was light.
[grunts]
[Azrael]
Your judgment is at hand.
[Kobra member grunts]
And I, Azrael...
find you guilty!
[guns cocking, firing]
[screams in pain]
[all gasp]
What in the hell?
[grunts]
[screams]
[suspenseful music playing]
[tires screeching]
[thud]
[screaming]
[crash]
[screams]
Which way?
How should I know? Maybe--
[grunts]
[Chen screaming]
[panting]
[Azrael] Defiler.
Evil.
Your cult of serpents
must be punished.
Please... please don't.
I promise. I'll change my ways.
Please!
[intense music playing]
Kali Yuga, thank you.
Stay down.
[Azrael grunting]
[panting]
[grunts]
[Tony screams]
[Azrael grunting]
[horn honking]
- [tires screech]
- [Tony grunts]
Someone call 911!
[Azrael] No... No, not this.
Not again.
[Jean-Paul shudders]
Please.
You have to help me.
You have to.
[sobbing]
[theme music playing]
[eerie music playing]
[woman labored screaming]
[panting]
[screaming continues]
Come on. Push woman, push!
- That's it, that's it.
- [screaming]
C'mon, c'mon. Push!
[screaming]
[baby crying]
[sighing in exhaustion]
[gasps]
[in Spanish] Tell me.
[in English] It's...
It's a boy.
[crying] No, no!
It can't be true. No, please!
[crying] I'm so sorry, my child.
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- [baby crying]
[sad music playing]
[warden in Spanish]
Look, ma'am.
[in English] I do not make
the rules.
This is our way.
You and the boy must pay
for your husband's sins.
It isn't right!
Life rarely is.
[crying]
[indistinct chatter]
- Oh, now what do we have here?
- Huh?
[grunts in pain]
Hey!
[laughing maniacally]
Right now, I'm gonna
have a little snack.
[laughs]
What? Where is it?
[laughing]
Oh, you think that's funny?
[prisoner screaming]
[suspenseful music playing]
[panting]
Momma!
[coughing]
Momma.
Here, eat.
What have I told you? Huh?
No weakness. No pity.
Even for me.
You want to be kind
to your mama?
Then survive. Dominate.
Subjugate! [coughing]
- [in Spanish] But mom...
- No.
[in English] You do not make me
strong by showing me mercy.
If I am to live, I must want to.
If you are to live,
you must want to.
[coughing]
This is the way of the world.
[wheels squeaking]
[gasps] He's here.
I found something for you.
- What is it?
- An old magazine.
But it talks about Gotham City.
A place
with the prettiest women...
and handsome-looking men and
skyscrapers as high
as the eye can see.
It's a place a boy
could become a man.
- Here.
- "Gotham Today.
The strength
of Thomas Wayne..."
- [woman coughing]
- Thank you.
Of course.
How is your mother?
Sick.
Oh... I am sorry.
But if you need me,
I'll be here.
Look, Momma.
I have something new to read.
A wonder.
I thought you have read
everything they have.
Why?
Why do we read?
Because knowledge is strength.
And strength is survival.
Yes.
Good.
What is it about?
Someone named Thomas Wayne.
He lives in Gotham City.
I have heard of him.
He is a powerful man.
A strong man.
You could be a man like him.
[scoffs] Not from
inside these walls.
[coughing] Then grow.
Grow until these walls
cannot hold you.
Till you burst free.
Then you can show the world...
people like this Thomas Wayne,
what true strength is.
[coughing]
I will, Momma.
I'll make them bow before me.
And then, I'll give you
a palace in the sky.
The world will know
our name, Momma.
Someday,
we'll go to this Gotham,
and it will be ours.
Don't worry.
Someday, it will be ours.
[wheels squeaking]
Mmm...
I heard about your mother.
[clicks tongue]
You're all alone now.
[door sliding]
Well, I know you must be sad,
but I can comfort you.
It's good to let others
carry your burdens.
[boy grunts]
That is weakness!
The strong carry
their own burdens.
And the weak,
they deserve what they get.
[grunts]
[book man choking]
[boy panting]
Hey!
[boy grunting]
[guard] Calm down!
Boy...
what have you done?
[biting, screaming]
[warden screaming]
[in Spanish] Goddamn it!
[in English] That is not a boy.
That's a demon.
A bane
to everything that is holy.
Take him.
Place him in the Cavidad Oscuro.
[screaming]
[thud]
[coughing]
It would be a mercy
to kill you quickly... Bane.
But there is no more mercy here.
The government forbids me
from executing you,
but I have other ways.
Don't worry.
No one has survived
the Cavidad Oscuro for long.
[mouse squeaking]
So your stay
will be a short one.
Here's something for you
to pass what little time
you have left.
[grunts]
[grunting]
- [panting]
- [squeaking]
[laughs]
[in Spanish] Ah, look at that.
[in English] You have friends!
[laughs] Hiciste amigos.
[warden laughing]
I see the hate burning
in your eyes, boy.
Let's hope it's enough
to keep you warm.
[laughing callously]
[squeaking]
[grunts]
[instrumental music playing]
[inhaling and exhaling]
[gate opens]
[prisoners speaking
indistinctly]
[prisoner] Is that the kid?
How long has he been down there?
Forever.
If he can survive, so can we.
He has shown us.
[electrical beeping]
You are a survivor,
which means you are strong.
And we need strong men.
Our government
has created something.
Something that will
make our soldiers more than...
mortal.
If we can find someone
strong enough to withstand it.
We've had little success so far.
But maybe you
will be different, eh?
This is your chance to pay
for the sins of your father.
It is called "Venom."
And with it,
we will return Santa Prisca
to its former glory.
[anguished grunting]
[screaming]
[in Spanish] Our glory.
[monitor beeping rapidly]
[grunting]
[beeping accelerating]
[continuous beep]
Ah...
[in English] I thought
he would survive
where the others could not.
No matter.
I have an entire building
of unwilling guinea pigs.
[steady beeping]
[grunts]
[anguished screams]
[guard screaming]
No, no! [screams]
[grunts] Please... don't...
- [gunshot]
- [screaming]
Please, I...
I'll give you anything.
Just let me live.
[speaking Spanish]
[in English] Live?
You do not know what it means
to live. It is not a right.
It is a prize...
A prize which must be won!
Please. [grunts]
I should thank you.
You made me survive.
Made me embrace the darkness.
Learn what true strength is.
And now I must give
others that gift.
What...
What are you?
What you said,
"a demon, an abomination.
A bane to everything
that is holy."
[alarm beeping]
Surrender!
No.
[guard] No, por favor... No!
- [guard screaming]
- [gunfire]
[buzzer sounds]
[prisoners chanting] Bane!
Bane! Bane! Bane! Bane!
[chanting continues]
[Shondra] So,
what gives you hope, Mr. Wayne?
[Bruce Wayne] Now?
Well, I hope
we can move this along
so I can go back to work.
Please take this seriously.
Oh, I am.
I thought you were
supposed to help me
with some of my
more serious physical problems.
In order to do what I do,
to heal the body,
we have to make sure
we heal the mind.
So, as I was saying,
what gives you hope?
I don't know.
A good scotch.
A nice watch.
Uh-huh.
If you won't start,
maybe I should.
Mr. Wayne, I did a deep dive
on you the other day.
- I'm flattered.
- Don't be.
What I found
was really quite interesting.
The tabloids reported
you had a falling out
with your son, Dick Grayson?
[Bruce] It was...
It was time for him to move on.
And then your second ward,
Jason Todd?
By your own admission,
a hard case.
Well...
I'm sorry for your loss.
And you mentioned
a new intern at work. Tim?
He's... um...
Smart. Determined.
- In need?
- I'm sorry.
I don't really understand--
Oh, Mr. Wayne.
Bruce, please.
Mr. Wayne,
we both know you understand.
You may have all of your board,
the media, whatever debutante
you take out on the town fooled.
But I've been listening to you
for a few days,
and I know
how intelligent you are.
I know the mask you put on
for those around you.
I'm here because I thought
you might be able to help me
with some of my physical issues.
No. You're here because
your surrogate father
said he'd quit
if you didn't find help.
I want to help you, Mr. Wayne.
And in order for me to help,
I need to know
what and who I'm helping.
I see.
I'll make sure you're paid
for wasting your time.
When I ask you
what gives you hope,
it seems obvious to me.
But you don't seem to see it.
Enlighten me.
People. Helping people.
It's obvious from your own
personal tragedies
that you're working out
the trauma you experienced
as a little boy
by helping others.
What's fascinating, however,
is that you don't
recognize the need
to be helped in return.
Instead, you continue to think
these people would be lost
without you.
Which makes you,
if I can be blunt...
You weren't before?
It makes you a control freak
with a messiah complex.
You need help, Mr. Wayne.
And if you don't ask for it,
something's going to break.
And things that break
aren't easily put back together.
[prisoner screaming]
Cell 113, secured.
Cell 114, secured.
[Mad Hatter] Secure?
If I was secure,
I'm sure they'd let me out.
I am late for a tea party,
after all. [laughs maniacally]
- [sighs] Nutball.
- [metal door clangs]
[suspenseful music playing]
Stan?
I just heard a noise
in the east wing.
Is that you?
Stan?
Stan, this isn't funny.
[Mad Hatter] Ohh...
Well, maybe
you're going bonkers.
But I'll tell you
a little secret,
all the best people are.
[laughs]
Shut up, Hatter!
Stan!
Okay, I'm pulling the alarm.
You hear me?
[Bane growling]
I hear you.
[cracking]
[guard struggling]
[Mad Hatter] Ohh...
I might make the tea party
after all.
[singing]
♪ I'm going to the party ♪
[laughing maniacally]
[suspenseful music playing]
[beeping]
[timer beeping]
The liberation of Gotham begins.
[explosion]
[tires screeching]
[grunts]
Shouldn't you slow down?
No.
[engine accelerating]
I didn't mean driving.
I meant...
You haven't slept since Arkham
exploded two days ago.
You need to rest.
I'll rest when everyone
that's escaped is captured.
Not before.
[tires screech]
Right now, we're all that stands
between those inmates
and the fall of Gotham.
Well, maybe we should ask
Jean-Paul for help.
His training is coming along
and he hasn't
had an outburst in--
I told you, he's a bomb
that needs to be defused.
The only reason
he's in the cave is that
we have a chance to help him
where no one else would.
We just need to keep
an eye on him,
to give him purpose,
to show him his skills
can be a blessing
instead of a curse.
We're here.
[tires screech]
Stay put.
What? I'm coming with you.
No, you're not.
Man the aerial drone. Relay
anything that might warrant it.
[swishing]
Yes, sir.
[whirring]
[whooshes]
North of your location,
it looks like Mad Hatter
is having a party.
Yes, yes.
You're all doing splendidly.
Now, I think it's time
for dessert.
Everyone, you see
the knives in front of you?
Pick them up.
[knives clinking]
You all had a hand
in sending me to Arkham.
So why not use those hands
to kill yourselves?
[laughs maniacally]
[dramatic music playing]
[knives clinking]
[Mad Hatter]
Oh, look, it's Batman.
Hello, dear.
How nice of you to join us.
Come on, sit down.
Sit down.
Would you like
a nice cup of tea?
Mad Hatter, the party's over.
Over?
But, we just got here.
My friends are wearing
their party hats,
and now they'll do
whatever I want them to do.
And what I want them to do,
is play a favorite game
of a friend of mine.
Off with your head.
Off with your head!
[laughs maliciously]
[grunting and groaning]
[Mad Hatter
continues laughing maliciously]
[grunting]
[Mad Hatter] Oh!
My days!
I've never seen that before.
Well, Batman,
you've really lost your touch.
I expected more
from the Dark Knight.
[laughs maniacally]
[crackling]
[groans]
What? Where am I?
[grunting and groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
This party is getting boring.
Let's end the night with a bang!
[laughs maniacally]
[grunting]
You insolent-- [grunts]
[squeals]
I told you to wait in the car.
I'm sorry. I... It looked like
you needed some help.
Hmm.
[suspenseful music playing]
[exhales deeply]
[groans]
- [Jean-Paul] No!
- [Alfred] Jean-Paul?
Are you all right?
Alfred.
[laughs quietly]
Yes.
Yes, I think so.
Take heart.
You lasted longer
than last time,
and the time before that.
All in all, you're making
tremendous progress.
Yes, but...
Uh, what they did to me, Alfred.
I had a life before Azrael.
Before the Order of Dumas.
At least I thought I did.
Now I...
I don't know who or...
what I am.
You are a man that was abused
by this Order of Dumas...
Your father.
What they did
was unconscionable.
But we'll fix it, my boy.
Batman does not take people
into his confidence lightly.
You're here because he thinks
it's the best place
for you to heal, to recover.
And you're well on your way.
In the meantime,
may I recommend doing
what we Englishmen do
when things get a bit rough?
What's that?
Have a spot of tea.
[engine revs]
[tires screech]
I was not trying to disobey you.
I just... It looked like
you needed help, that's all.
What I need is for you
to follow orders.
Look into what caused
the explosion at Arkham.
Ask Jean-Paul.
Maybe his considerable
computer skills can be of use.
I should be in the field and--
Right. Understood.
Master Bruce,
may I make you some food, sir?
No, Alfred,
I'm just back to resupply.
Sir, if I may,
you are looking a bit weary.
You need to sleep.
I'm sure the Arkham escapees
would love that,
but I can't give them a break.
Not now.
Radio in if you find anything.
He's tired, Tim.
I'm sure you'll be back out
on patrol in no time.
I know.
I'm just worried.
He's been going nonstop
for two days.
That's a long time with no rest,
even for Batman.
Yes, you're right, of course.
Since you'll be staying here
for the evening,
shall I tell your father
that you'll be working late?
I'm not staying here.
Master Bruce wanted you
to stay in the Batcave.
He didn't say stay
in the Batcave.
He said, "Figure out
how Arkham exploded
with Jean-Paul." And that's
exactly what we're gonna do.
I don't think Master Bruce
will take kindly
to your semantic loophole.
If Batman's gonna
push himself to the edge,
I have to try to help him
as best I can.
I need to check out
the bomb site in person.
I'll be careful, I promise.
And Jean-Paul?
Does he really need to go?
He's been stuck in here
for weeks. Batman said,
"We have to show him
there's more he can do."
Besides, I don't have
a driver's license
and I kinda need a lift.
[sirens wailing]
[Montoya] Zsasz is a killer.
Every minute we are out here
puts those women in danger.
I'm not sending my men in there
to be killed one at a time.
We wait.
For what? Your vigilante friend
to show up?
I'll, uh, check on SWAT's ETA.
Commissioner,
we are paid to stand
in harm's way.
That's the job.
Some day, he won't be here
to clean up our city's mess,
and it's gonna be up to us.
We know what to do.
Just let us do it.
There's a difference between
what we do and what he does.
If that day comes,
the one you're describing,
Detective Montoya,
where he's not here to fight
these crazies,
Gotham City
will already be lost.
And there won't be a damn thing
we can do about it.
I'll check the perimeter.
[sirens wailing]
Don't prove me wrong.
[suspenseful music playing]
[grunting]
[suspenseful music continues]
[woman screaming]
Please, no! Please, no!
[screams]
- Please.
- Come here, zombie.
Let my blade have a look at you.
Please. Please don't.
You spend so much time
on your face,
your hair, your makeup.
It's all so pointless.
Your existence is pointless.
Just another zombie.
But I'm here,
here to set you free
from your meaningless life!
Isn't that wonderful?
Freeze!
Put the gun down, zombie,
or this pretty smile
gets a whole lot wider.
Let the girl go, Zsasz!
Why? So she can keep doing
the same things over and over?
Not gonna happen, zombie.
[woman whimpers]
Take me.
Take me instead.
A hero?
How sweet.
[Montoya] The gun's down.
I'm right here.
[slurps] Well, I'm sure
you'll taste sweet too.
All that blue blood.
[knife swishes]
[groans]
What did your sacrifice get you?
Hmm?
After you're dead,
I'll move on to the rest,
and nothing on this earth
can stop me.
[dramatic music playing]
Oh, look at him, zombie.
You can see it, can't you?
He's just like me.
A predator.
He's not like you.
He doesn't kill.
He doesn't?
How can you be sure?
Oh, look at him...
tired, wavering...
How long before he gives in
to his darker desires?
Oh, come on, let's find out.
What do you say?
I say...
you talk too much.
[grunts]
[laughing maniacally]
You have the hostages?
Go!
[suspenseful music playing]
[inhales deeply]
[grunting and groaning]
[Batman groans]
[Zsasz] Predator...
like me.
[grunting and groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
Batman! Stop!
I...
Is he dead?
Just... like... me.
- [laughs]
- No.
I... I...
I need to go.
You almost killed him.
If this is how you help,
you're no better than they are.
[swishing]
What the hell happened, Montoya?
Your hero, Commissioner,
he's losing control.
[suspenseful music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[car doors close]
Are you sure
I need to wear this?
Can't have anyone linking you
to me or Batman, you know?
[suspenseful music playing]
What exactly are we looking for?
Evidence.
Reports said that
it was a gas explosion.
But GCPD, fire,
everyone seems to be
stretched thin.
I'm guessing they barely
looked this place over
before they headed
to their next emergency.
[suspenseful music continues]
Hey, Robin, what's this?
[Robin] Huh.
That's unusual.
What is?
The burn pattern here.
Or the lack of one.
Like something exploded out.
Look, see the scorch marks
moving upward
almost in a sphere shape.
This was a bomb.
Some sort of multiple plastique.
How do you know all this stuff?
You're just a kid.
A kid that loves
mysteries, puzzles.
I may never be the detective
that Batman is,
but I'm definitely gonna
give him a run for his money.
Here. Look.
There's the detonator.
A little of
the explosive residue.
And...
That's a spectrometer.
Yes, a very expensive
portable one.
Hey, looks like you haven't
forgotten everything
from your past.
It's all jumbled, like a puzzle.
Bits and pieces
that come and go.
I know, but don't worry,
it will all come back,
I promise.
But until then,
I appreciate your help.
Well, beats midterms.
[beeping]
I've seen this particular
brand of explosive before.
A couple weeks ago, a member
of the Bertinelli crime family
used it on an armored car,
which means...
Another field trip?
You read my mind.
[suspenseful music playing]
[henchman] It's been
a couple of days, boss.
You must've worked up a riddle
that'll get us rich.
Riddle me this, boys.
Why was the loud hunter
mauled by his prey?
Hmm?
Because he didn't shut his trap.
No.
Something else
is going on out there.
A riddle I haven't
found the answer to.
We wait it out until the time--
[grunting]
No one sits out tonight.
Who...
You.
You are responsible
for all the chaos in Gotham.
[Bane] The chaos
has always been there.
I'm just helping
everyone rise above it.
And you...
I am helping you find out
what true strength is.
[suspenseful music playing]
[engine revs]
[glass breaking]
[dramatic music playing]
Scarface! No!
[grunts]
You're losing it, Bats.
Really losing it.
[groans]
[dramatic music playing]
[grunting]
I got him.
I got the Batman.
[screaming]
[Firefly laughs maniacally]
[grunting and groaning]
[swooshing]
[dramatic music continues]
[grunting and groaning]
[Batman sighs]
[Batman coughing]
Batman doesn't look so good.
No.
No, he doesn't.
[laughs wickedly]
[Jason] Failed me.
You failed me. You failed me.
You got me killed. [echoing]
No.
You're gonna get Tim killed.
Jean-Paul, Alfred.
[grunts]
This city would be
better off without you.
You're the reason
Gotham suffers!
[grunting]
This... isn't... real.
[groans]
[breathing heavily]
[somber music playing]
[thunder rumbling]
[line ringing]
[Shondra] Hello?
Hello?
Is anyone there?
Mr. Wayne?
Bruce.
Is that you?
I'm tired, Shondra.
[Shondra] Have you slept?
There's no time.
[Shondra] No time for what?
Bruce...
I want to help you,
but the first step
in getting help is to want it.
You called me for a reason.
I know your work is important.
I know that you've been
running yourself ragged.
But, Bruce,
you need to slow down.
Where are you?
In my car.
[Shondra] Good.
Come to the office.
I'm working late anyway,
and we can talk.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think I...
[dramatic music playing]
I have to go.
- Bruce, don't--
- [touchscreen beeps]
[engine revs]
[tires screech]
[door creaks]
[door closes]
[mysterious music playing]
[clock ticks loudly]
[beeping]
[The Riddler]
You figured it out!
"I am a king that works
every day,
every second, every hour,
every minute, day in day out."
[screeching]
"What am I?"
Welcome to
Crowning Clock Tower, Batman.
Nygma!
What...
What happened to you?
Another riddle. But the answer
isn't one you're going to like.
[loud grunting]
Hmm.
[laughs wickedly]
I can't feel a thing.
[grunting]
I can't feel... a thing.
What did he do to me?
[groaning]
[clock ticks loudly]
[Batman groaning]
[The Riddler] The bomb!
If I don't get out of here,
we're both going to die.
[grunts]
[dramatic music playing]
[bomb beeping]
[straining]
[grunts]
[glass shattering]
[bomb beeps]
[somber music playing]
Sergeant, take two men
and go down that alley.
[car starts]
[tires screech]
Nygma?
He ran off. Fast, too.
Looked like he was
hopped up on something.
He couldn't have gotten far.
Batman, are you okay?
Why wouldn't I be?
Look at you, you look like hell.
Besides...
I'm getting reports...
Of what?
You're off your game.
You're a little more
edgy than usual.
I'm fine.
Bullshit.
We've worked with
each other for years.
You're not fine.
Look,
if you ever need to talk,
I'm here.
[melancholy music playing]
[chomps loudly]
Tell him it's delicious,
would you, Gino?
Sure thing, boss. I can--
[groans]
[grunting and groaning]
[yelps]
[groaning]
[epic music playing]
You've got a lotta nerve,
bird boy.
Is this supposed
to mean something?
That's a piece of explosive
I found at Arkham.
I think it belongs to you.
That has nothing
to do with-- [groans]
[Robin] Sure it does.
Blow up Arkham,
let some crazies loose,
keep everyone busy.
But why?
To pull off a heist?
Kill a couple of
competing gangs?
I told you that wasn't me.
It was some other guy.
What other guy?
I don't know. [groans]
[Jean-Paul] Robin, is this--
Watch and learn.
[Franco groaning]
[choking] Okay!
Okay, I'll tell you what I know.
Last week, I got a call.
It was a dinner
for the five families.
I thought it was
to discuss business,
but as it turned out,
it was just to get us all
in the same room.
I didn't call this.
I thought you did, Vincent?
[chuckling] Like I wanna
see your faces
outside of Christmas Mass.
[all laughing]
[Franco] He stepped out of
the shadows so quick,
we didn't even notice.
He killed Vincent in a second,
- and then...
- [screams]
[Franco] Mayhem.
[whimpering]
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[choking]
[bones snapping]
[Franco]
He called himself "Bane."
Asked me
where we held our explosives.
Come on, what was I gonna do?
I swear, I thought
I was gonna die.
But he just looked at me...
like I was... less.
And then, he left.
[whimpering]
And that's why you
beefed up your security.
You're afraid he's coming back.
Yeah, but instead,
I got you. Too bad.
Move!
[groaning]
[dramatic music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[soft whimpering]
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, hey! It's okay.
You're okay.
No. I can't be here.
I can't!
[stammering] Just tell me what
you want and leave me alone.
Where'd you say
you kept those explosives?
[panting]
[groaning]
Are you okay?
No.
What I did was...
What you did is save us.
Batman was right.
These skills
can be used for good.
I didn't feel good, Robin.
I felt...
[whispering] Out of control.
I could've killed someone.
But you didn't.
The deprogramming is working,
Jean-Paul.
Look how far you've come.
Listen, I have to go
check out this lead.
Head back to the cave,
and when I get back,
we'll sort this out, okay?
[whooshing]
[melancholy music playing]
[music crescendos, then ends]
[knock on door]
[door creaks]
[groaning]
Bruce?
[Shondra grunts]
I'm sorry, I...
I didn't want to go home,
I thought--
What happened?
I was...
mugged.
You don't have to tell me
what happened,
but don't insult me
by lying about it.
Let me get something
for that wound.
I shouldn't have come.
I just need paper towels
and tape.
And then I'll leave.
- I'll pay for your time.
- What?
I said, I shouldn't have come.
I'm glad you did.
When you called earlier...
Lie back.
I was worried.
[Shondra sighs]
This is bad.
We should get you to a hospital.
No. No hospitals.
Okay...
Can I call someone? Alfred?
No.
He'll just make a fuss.
You're lucky to have someone
in your life to make a fuss.
This one is going
to need stitches.
I have a bandage that will stop
the bleeding as best I can,
but you need a doctor.
Just sit back and relax.
[exhales]
Here... Oh.
[inhales]
[exhales]
[suspenseful music playing]
It should be up ahead.
Well, what do we have here?
[Bane] Please,
come in and find out.
[Robin grunts]
[eerie music playing]
[electrical buzzing]
[Bane] You can dispense
with the subterfuge, Mr. Drake.
I know you're awake.
You must be Bane. [sighs]
What do you want?
[Bane] You are the detective.
You tell me.
What do I want?
[electrical buzzing]
You killed four
of the five crime families,
took their explosives,
destroyed Arkham.
[Bane] Well, go on.
Maybe you're trying
to start a gang war.
Or you were hired
by a rival mob.
Nothing so mundane.
[grunts]
Try again.
[Robin] You know who I am,
- so you must know who--
- [Bane] Yes.
I know what Mr. Wayne likes
to play at during the night.
It's a wonder that
more people don't know.
He does such a poor job
covering it up.
Him...
You're here for him.
[Bane] Mmm-hmm.
Arkham, the gangs...
the police will be stretched
so thin that
Batman will pick up the slack.
And you knew that.
You want him weak
so you can... what?
Kill him?
Break him.
You are better at this
than I gave you credit for.
But why?
Bruce Wayne
has crippled this city.
He has allowed
the weak to thrive.
His father knew that.
His strength built this city
into the envy of the world.
A dream that kept me going
for many years.
So, imagine my surprise
when I arrived to find
it has been turned into
- a cesspool of weakness...
- Come back!
- Hey! Aren't you gonna help me?
- ...and charity.
I wonder how Bruce's father
would feel
knowing that his son
is the reason...
- [grunts]
- ...it has become a city
of weaklings, vagrants,
and madmen.
I've come to fix this city.
The weak will perish
and the strong will thrive.
When Batman finds you
lifeless like the last Robin,
his spirit will
finally be broken.
And I can get rid of the thing
that is holding Gotham back
from its return to greatness.
[groaning]
[groans]
So you're crazy,
just like the rest of them.
[grunting]
[Robin grunts]
[screaming]
[coughing]
[Bane] Oh, I think you'll find
I am nothing
like the rest of them.
[Robin screaming]
[grunts]
[neck cracks]
[intense music playing]
[grunting]
[straining]
[Bane growling]
[breathing heavily]
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pattering]
[Jean-Paul sighs]
Father, forgive me.
I...
Tonight I remembered...
all of it. I...
I saw what I did.
And it was... horrible.
How can I live knowing that...
that there's something
inside of me
that can do such harm?
My son,
the Lord can take what is meant
for evil and turn it to good.
What is inside of you
is meant for something more.
Your experience, skills,
God can use those
to help the world
instead of hurting it.
- How?
- By accepting your destiny.
By becoming the knight
Saint Dumas wants you to be.
[Jean-Paul breathing heavily]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[thunder rumbling]
[breathing heavily]
[Jean-Paul screaming]
You are chosen.
Accept your destiny
and become that
which you are meant to be!
Azrael!
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pattering]
- [phone vibrating]
- [sighs]
[Shondra sighs]
Alfred?
[Alfred] Master Bruce, it's Tim.
He's been hurt.
[thunderclap]
[door creaks]
Huh?
Hmm.
[bats squeaking]
What happened?
I figured it out, Bruce,
who blew up Arkham.
Where's Jean-Paul?
He got spooked.
You should've seen him though.
He moved like lightning.
I think the system is triggered
in a life or death type
of scenario.
He took out half a dozen
of Bertinelli's men
in a couple of seconds.
It was crazy.
- What were you thinking?
- Master Bruce! I--
No. No, Alfred.
I told you to stay here.
Actually, you didn't.
- Your exact words--
- You knew what I meant!
You're not ready.
You could have gotten killed.
But I didn't.
And I found out who's creating
all this chaos in Gotham.
- They call him Bane, and--
- You're fired.
- What?
- Master Bruce.
Please,
let me get you some food.
No. I need a partner
that does what he's told.
I can't have another Robin die
because they don't
follow orders.
I'm not Jason.
No. You're not.
Get your things and leave.
Alfred will drive you home.
I'll have a talk with him.
He's just tired.
He'll come around.
I don't think so.
- [grunts]
- [shattering]
[sighs wearily]
[groaning in pain]
Alfred, Tim, I'm tired
and I shouldn't have said--
[thunderclap]
[suspenseful music playing]
Alfred! Tim!
[footsteps approaching]
[intense music playing]
Bane.
I have sought you out, Batman.
The son of Thomas Wayne,
a boy of privilege,
a boy of tragedy.
You are the weakness
that drowns this city
and I intend to break you.
Then give it your best shot.
Good.
[beeps]
[gas hissing]
[groaning]
[thunderclap]
[grunting]
[Batman grunts]
[groans]
They say you are
the greatest detective.
[neck cracks]
And yet you did not
see this coming.
[Batman grunting]
You are a crutch
this city relies upon.
But now it's time that they
stood on their own two feet.
[door creaks]
Yes...
Yes. I know you want to hide.
You are always hiding.
From the world...
from the people close to you.
Hiding from your own failure.
But you cannot hide
from destiny.
[groaning]
From me.
[Batman grunting]
[groaning]
[whimpers]
[growling]
[screams]
[intense music playing]
I have dreamt of you, Bruce.
Oh, I've dreamt of your family.
[Batman grunting]
[Bane] Of the strength
your father must have had
to build his empire.
[grunts]
An empire
you are not fit to rule
because you lack the strength.
[Batman grunts, coughing]
[Bane]
The strength to save Tim.
[shattering]
[Bane] Alfred.
The city.
Jason.
[Batman strained breathing]
Jason?
The strength
to save your parents.
Oh, how you let them die, Bruce,
while you sat in an alley,
mewling like a calf
as your parents bled
and their murderer
disappeared into the night.
Oh, you must be glad
they aren't alive
to see what you've become,
to see what you've
allowed Gotham to become.
[Batman grunting]
[Bane] Enough with your toys!
Face me with your fists!
[Bane laughing tauntingly]
[grunts in pain]
- [grunting]
- [Batman groaning in pain]
[Bane yelling]
Beg for mercy!
Scream my name!
Go to hell.
[groans in frustration]
I am Bane.
I could kill you,
but death
would only end your agony
and silence your shame.
Instead, I will simply...
[bones snapping]
[gasping]
Break you.
[strained breathing]
[helicopter hovering,
sirens wailing]
What happened?
Explosion of some kind.
Everyone is evacuated
- and Fire is on the way.
- [siren blaring]
Of course, the press
is having a field day.
I think every station
in town is here.
[siren wailing]
Any luck?
No.
He's not answering.
I should go.
Bruce...
[intense music playing]
Get one of those floodlights
on the second story roof!
Who the hell is this guy?
Now, Gotham,
you must do what you
haven't done for a generation.
Fend for yourself!
Batman?
[officers yell]
[intense music playing]
Take him out!
[gunfire]
That can't...
that can't be Batman, can it?
What's going to happen
to the city?
Get back! Everyone, get back!
Move!
[Bullock] Good God.
This place is about
to become hell on earth.
[somber music playing]
[siren wailing]
[closing theme music playing]